#### Contact

jill.casewirth@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jill-case-wirth-9560977 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Change Management
Healthcare Management
Leadership

# Jill Case-Wirth

Senior Vice President & Chief Nurse Executive at WellStar Health System

Greater Atlanta Area

### Summary

Jill Case-Wirth is an accomplished Nurse Executive with proven success leading teams in the achievement of a vision for transforming and creating value in healthcare. She has expertise in Lean leadership, strategic planning, innovation and process redesign, creating measureable and sustained results. A passion for the Profession and Practice of Nursing, and the vital role performed in the delivery of patient care. Experience creating an environment where nurses collaborate with physicians and an interdisciplinary team to improve quality, reduce the cost of care, and enhance the patient experience. She held the Vice President of Clinical Services and Chief Nursing Officer from 2011 to May of 2014. In her role, she served as a key member of the leadership team to manage the organization's rapid growth and increasing complexity around clinical transformation and care coordination, while continuing to improve patient outcomes, throughput and overall operations.

As member of the executive leadership team, she led and sponsored many break through strategic initiatives. Establishing an Interdisciplinary Model of Clinical Governance, improving Medication Administration safety by 50% year over year; established a Clinical Workforce Model that received the New North Workforce Excellence Award in 2013; led EMR integration, led Perioperative redesign, and launched a plan to improve the Patient Experience. In collaboration with others, redesigned and built of a \$90 million hospital using Lean knowledge and tools to support an innovative model of care that is nationally recognized.

She earned her bachelor of science in nursing from the University of Wisconsin- Madison and her master of healthcare administration from Cardinal Stritch University.

She's a member of the American Nurses Association, American Organization of Nurse Executives, Wisconsin Organization of Nurse Executives, and the CNO Advisory Board for Press Ganey.

## Experience

WellStar Health System
Senior Vice President & Chief Nurse Executive
November 2014 - Present (5 years 9 months)
Marietta, GA

Thedacare
14 years 2 months

Former Vice President of Clinical Services/CNO November 2007 - May 2014 (6 years 7 months) Appleton, WI

Executive Director of Home Health April 2000 - November 2007 (7 years 8 months) Appleton, WI

Meriter Health Service
Director of Home Health Services
January 1981 - April 2000 (19 years 4 months)

Madison General Hospital
Head Nurse
January 1983 - June 1994 (11 years 6 months)
Leader of a 27 bed inpatient pediatric unit; and 3 bed ICU.

Mayo Clinic Staff Registered Nurse August 1980 - January 1983 (2 years 6 months) Rochester, MN

Registered Nurse on inpatient Neurology, and Pediatrics. Progressive leadership responsibilities as charge nurse. Specialty in Pediatric Oncology

#### Education

Cardinal Stritch University

Master's Degree, Health/Health Care Administration/Management · (2003)

University of Wisconsin-Madison BSN, Nursing · (1976 - 1980)